Guide to the Arthur Judson Brown Papers
Yale University Divinity School Library
- Correspondence, 1864-1967; Series I
  Correspondence Re: Birthdays: Material in this section is arranged chronologically (e.g., 70th Birthday, 80th Birthday, etc.) The individual greetings for each occasion are filed alphabetically according to writer. Telegrams are integrated with correspondence if less than five were received for one birthday. Numerous telegrams, however, are located in separate folders after correspondence.
  Correspondence Re: Retirement: The material in this section is filed alphabetically according to the first letter of the writer's surname.
  The material concerning Arthur J. Brown's 1922 and 1940 operations appears chronologically, while the contents of each folder are arranged according to the first letter of the writer's surname.
  The sympathy correspondence is arranged alphabetically according to the name of the deceased. Within each folder material is filed alphabetically according to the first letter of the writer's surname.
  - Correspondence: General
    - A, 1906-1907, 1921-1960 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Allen, Horace Newton, 1901 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - American Committee on Religious Rights and Minorities, 1920-1937 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - American Council for Promoting International Peace through the Churches, 1925-1926 (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - Atkinson, Henry A., 1931, 1938, 1947 (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - Atkinson, Marjorie Weber (Mrs. Henry A.), 1959, 1961 (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - Bangor Seminary - Board of Missionary Preparation, 1915-1958 (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - Boughton - Butler, 1901, 1915, 1946-1958 (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - Balfour, Alexander Hugh Bruce, 1910 (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - x-ref. Board of Foreign Missions, Presby terian Church (United) in the U.S.A. See: Presbyterian Church (United) in the U.S.A. - Board of Foreign Missions
    - Brilioth, Ygnve Torgny, 1921, 1950 (Box 1, Folder 10)
    - Bryan, William Jennings, 1910-1920, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 11)
    - Bryce, James, 1921 (Box 1, Folder 12)
    - Buttrick, George A., 1953-1954, 1959 (Box 1, Folder 13)
    - Cadman - Christian Science Monitor, 1906-1958 (Box 1, Folder 14)
    - Clark - Curtice, 1900-1933, 1957,1959, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 15)
    - Carnegie, Louise W. (Mrs. Andrew) x-ref. Capen, Samuel B. See: Series IV, Folder 17, 1925,1928, 1937-1946 (Box 1, Folder 16)
    - Chi Alpha Fraternity, 1958, 1962 (Box 1, Folder 17)
    - Chinese Legation, 1900,1903, 1917, 1922 (Box 1, Folder 18)
    - x-ref. Church Peace Union See: Council on Religion and International Affairs
    - Cleveland, Grover, 1898 (Box 1, Folder 19)
    - Columbia University Oral History Project, including ms., 1956 (Box 1, Folder 20)
    - Corbin, John C., 1952, 1962-1963 (Box 1, Folder 21)
    - Council on Religion and Inter- national Affairs See also: Henry A. Atkinson, 1938,1947, 1957-1962 (Box 1, Folder 22)
    - D, 1900-1961 (Box 1, Folder 23)
    - Damrong (Prince), 1902-1929, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 24)
    - de Hortley, Nicholas, 1921 (Box 1, Folder 25)
    - Devawongee, Varopakar See also: Series IV, Folder g, 1902 (Box 1, Folder 26)
    - Dickinson, Willoughby H., 1925-1926, 1940 (Box 1, Folder 27)
    - x-ref. Dodge, Phelps See: Series IV, Folder 37
    - E, 1912,1923-1935,1955, 1961 (Box 1, Folder 28)
    - Ecumenical Conference of 1900, re: Hospitality Committee See also: Elihu Root (Box 1, Folder 29)
    - F, 1902,1916, 1953-1962 (Box 1, Folder 30)
    - Fairbanks, Charles W., 1913, 1916 (Box 1, Folder 31)
    - Finley, John H., 1926-1937 (Box 1, Folder 32)
    - Ford, George B., 1955-1961 (Box 1, Folder 33)
    - Foreign Missions Conference of North America, Committee of Reference and Counsel, incl. re: Korea See also: Elihu Root, 1915, 1916 (Box 1, Folder 34)
    - Fordick, Harry Emerson, 1912,1938, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 35)
    - Foster, John W. See also: Series IV, Folder 17 ref. Fowler, John See: Yuan Shih Kai, and, 1908-1916 (Box 1, Folder 36)
    - G, 1905-1922, 1958-1962, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 37)
    - German Evangelical Church Federation See: American Council for Promoting International Friendship through the Churches
    - x-ref. ref. Greek Legation See: Series IV, Folder 7
    - Gustaf (Prince), 1925, 1927 (Box 1, Folder 38)
    - H, 1901, 1924-1962 (Box 1, Folder 39)
    - Hadley, Arthur T., 1907-1913 (Box 1, Folder 40)
    - Hall of Fame for Great Americans, 1915, 1944-1962 (Box 1, Folder 41)
    - Harrison, Benjamin, 1897-1900 (Box 1, Folder 42)
    - Hart, Robert, 1901 (Box 1, Folder 43)
    - Hay, John See also: Series IV, Folder 17, 1900, 1904 (Box 1, Folder 44)
    - Hoover, Herbert See also: American Committee on Religious Rights and Minorities, 1920-1921, 1957-1958 (Box 1, Folder 45)
    - Hughes, Charles Evans See also: American Committee on Religious Rights and Minorities, 1921-1924 (Box 1, Folder 46)
    - Hungarian Legation (Royal), 1922,1926, 1936, 1938 (Box 1, Folder 47)
    - I, 1911-1912, 1948, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 48)
    - J, 1921-1936, 1959-1960, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 49)
    - K, 1910, 1938-1962 (Box 1, Folder 50)
    - x-ref. Kapler, D. Dr. See: American Council for Promoting International Peace through the Churches
    - x-ref. Komatsu, M. See: Foreign Missions Conference of North America, Com mittee of Reference and Counsel, and Alfred E. Marling
    - L, 1909-1962 (Box 1, Folder 51)
    - Lane Seminary, 1903 (Box 1, Folder 52)
    - Layman Is National Committee, 1956-1957 (Box 1, Folder 53)
    - League to Enforce Peace, 1916 (Box 1, Folder 54)
    - Lodge, Henry Cabot, 1921, 1924 (Box 1, Folder 55)
    - Louise (Crown Princess), 1938 (Box 1, Folder 56)
    - Luce, Henry R., 1959 (Box 1, Folder 57)
    - McConnell - Maryville College, 1907-1940, 1951-1952 (Box 2, Folder 58)
    - Mears - Mount, 1908, 1916-1923, 1954 1960 (Box 2, Folder 59)
    - MacKay, John A., 1945-1959 (Box 2, Folder 60)
    - x-ref. McKinley, William See: Series IV, Folder 17
    - Mahan, Alfred Thayer, 1912, 1914 (Box 2, Folder 61)
    - Marquis, A.N. Company (incl. Who's Who, Inc.), 1920, 1948, 1960 (Box 2, Folder 62)
    - Meletios, Archbishop, 1921 - 1922 (Box 2, Folder 63)
    - Missionary Review of the World, 1930 (Box 2, Folder 64)
    - Morgenthau, Henry, 1936-1943 (Box 2, Folder 65)
    - Mott, John R. See also: Foreign Missions Conference of North America, Committee of Reference and Counsel, 1900-1915, 1935,1951-1953 (Box 2, Folder 66)
    - N, 1906,1916, 1958, 1961 (Box 2, Folder 67)
    - x-ref. New York Times See: John Finley
    - O, 1907, 1928 (Box 2, Folder 68)
    - P, 1899-1911, 1924-1938, 1950-1962 (Box 2, Folder 69)
    - Presbyterian Church, First - Neenah, Ws., Newburg, Ore., Oak Park, Il., Portland, Ore., 1929-1933, 1953-1961 (Box 2, Folder 70)
    - Presbyterian Church (United) in the U.S.A. - Board of Foreign Missions, Board of Ministerial Relief and Susten ation, Synod of Missouri, Synod of Oregon; See also: Roy E. Vale, 1909-1928, 1947,1959,1962 (Box 15, Folder 71)
    - R, 1913, 1923-1930, 1940 1941, 1952-1960 (Box 15, Folder 72)
    - Reischauer, Edwin O., 1961 (Box 15, Folder 73)
    - Re: Ritchie Youth Center, Tallmadge, Oh., 1961 (Box 15, Folder 74)
    - Rockefeller, John D. Jr., 1928-1929, 1938 (Box 15, Folder 75)
    - Roosevelt, Theodore, 1900-1907 (Box 15, Folder 76)
    - Root, Elihu, 1900, 1907, 1913 (Box 15, Folder 77)
    - Sampson - Smiley, 1899,1910, 1930,1947-1962, n.d. (Box 15, Folder 78)
    - Smith - Swan, 1904-1905, 1920-1938,1953-1962 (Box 15, Folder 79)
    - Schieffelin, William Jay, 1936-1949 (Box 15, Folder 80)
    - x-ref. Siamese Legation See: Series IV, Folder 8
    - Simons, Walter, and Erna R., 1926,1929, 1937 (Box 15, Folder 81)
    - Sockman, Ralph See also: Hall of 19L7- Fame for Great Americans, 1962 (Box 15, Folder 82)
    - Soderblom, Nathan, 1922- 1926 (Box 15, Folder 83)
    - Speer, Robert and Emma B., 1901-1902, 1934-1937,1947-1948 (Box 15, Folder 84)
    - Stimson, Henry L., 1906, 1940 (Box 15, Folder 85)
    - T, 1901, 1916-1931, 1949 1958 (Box 2, Folder 86)
    - Taft, William H., 1906-1926 (Box 2, Folder 87)
    - Tuskegee Normal and Industrial Institute, 1903, 1924 (Box 2, Folder 88)
    - U, 1909, 1961-1962 (Box 2, Folder 89)
    - U.S. War Department, re: Grave of Edwin T. Brown, 1900 (Box 2, Folder 90)
    - Universal Christian Conference on Life Work, American Section Continuation Committee, re: speech made by Dr. Brown before Crown Prince Gustaf of Sweden, 1926 (Box 2, Folder 91)
    - V, 1899-1902, 1949, 1962 (Box 2, Folder 92)
    - Vale, Roy E., 1923-1924, 1945-1946,1957 (Box 2, Folder 93)
    - Venizelos, E.K., 1919-1922 (Box 2, Folder 94)
    - Walker - Westminster, 1901,1916-1936,1961-1962 (Box 2, Folder 95)
    - Whitehead - Wysham, 1900, 1925-1962 (Box 2, Folder 96)
    - Wabash College, 1914-1921, 1946-1961 (Box 2, Folder 97)
    - Wachtmeister, Axel, 1922, 1925 (Box 2, Folder 98)
    - Wanamaker, John, 1907, 1909 (Box 2, Folder 99)
    - x-ref. Washington, Booker T. See: Tuskegee Normal and Industrial Institute
    - Welsh, Herbert, 1952, 1962 (Box 2, Folder 100)
    - Wheeler, W. Reginald, 1924, 1955, 1960 (Box 2, Folder 101)
    - Wilson, Woodrow, 1903-1920 (Box 2, Folder 102)
    - Winton, Theodore, 1916-1929 (Box 2, Folder 103)
    - Wise, Stephen See also: American Jewish Congress, 1927-1928, 1948 (Box 2, Folder 104)
    - x-ref. Woolley, Mary E. See: Mount Holyoke College
    - World Missionary Conference, 1910 (Box 2, Folder 105)
    - Y.M.C.A. - Portland, Or., Yale University - Divinity School, 1895, 1922 (Box 2, Folder 106)
    - Yuan Shih Kai See also: Series IV, Folder 17, 1901, 1912 (Box 2, Folder 107)
    - Unidentified correspondence in Chinese and (Siamese?) (Box 2, Folder 108)
  - Correspondence: Family
    - Abraham Brown to Elizabeth Marsh Brown re: death of Edwin T. Brown, 1864 (Box 3, Folder 109)
    - Arthur J. Brown to Elliott W. Brown re: election as Sec'y of Pres. Board of Foreign Missions, 1895 (Box 3, Folder 110)
    - to: Jennie T. Brown (Mrs. Arthur J.), 1901-1925 (Box 3, Folder 111)
    - to and from: Jennie T. Brown (Mrs. Arthur J.), 1926 (Box 3, Folder 112)
    - to and from: Arthur J. Brown, Arthur J. Brown, Jr., Eleanor Brown, Jennie T. Brown (Mrs. Arthur J.), Harold Coe Stuart, 1927, 1943-1966 (Box 3, Folder 113)
    - re: the diaries of Arthur J. Brown (one letter, two notes), 1967, n.d. (Box 3, Folder 114)
    - unidentified, n.d. (Box 3, Folder 115)
  - Correspondence Re: Publications
    - "Lessons of Hard Times" Morning Oregonian (1893) (Box 4, Folder 116)
    - "Vacation on Mt. Hood" New York Evangelist (1893) (Box 4, Folder 117)
    - Report on Visits to Missions in China, Korea, Philippines, Siam, and Syria (pamphlets and volume) (1902), 1902 Mar-Jul (Box 4, Folder 118)
    - Report on Visits to Missions in China, Korea, Philippines, Siam, and Syria (pamphlets and volume) (1902), 1902 Aug-Dec (Box 4, Folder 119)
    - Report on Visits to Missions in China, 1903-1904, 191S, Korea, Philippines, Siam, and Syria (pamphlets and volume) (1902) (Box 4, Folder 120)
    - New Era in the Phillipines (1903), 1903-1905, 1908,1919, n.d. (Box 4, Folder 121)
    - New Forces in Old China (1904), 1904-1907, 1909, n.d. (Box 4, Folder 122)
    - "Truth and Falsehoods About Korea Missionaries" (1904) (Box 4, Folder 123)
    - The Why and How of Foreign Missions (1906), 1908-1909, 1919-1920,1922 (Box 4, Folder 124)
    - The Foreign Missionary (1907), 1907-1909, 1938,1958-1961, n.d. (Box 4, Folder 125)
    - The Nearer and Farther East (1908), 1910, 1913 (Box 4, Folder 126)
    - Report on a Second Visit to China, Japan, and Korea (1909), 1910-1911 (Box 4, Folder 127)
    - The Chinese Revolution ( 1912) (Box 4, Folder 128)
    - "The Korean Conspiracy Case" (1912), 1912-1913 (Box 4, Folder 129)
    - "The American Churches and the European War: A Message from the Church Peace Union" (1915) (Box 4, Folder 130)
    - Rising Churches in Non-Christian- Lands ( 1915) (Box 4, Folder 131)
    - Unity and Missions (1915), 1915-1916, 1920,1927, n.d. (Box 4, Folder 132)
    - Russia in Transformation (1917), 1917-1918, 1928 (Box 4, Folder 133)
    - The Mastery of the Far East (1919), 1919-1920, 1924,1928,1958 (Box 4, Folder 134)
    - "Prerequisites of Union" the Christian Work (1923) (Box 4, Folder 135)
    - Re: Address to General Assembly, Grand Rapids, MI (1924) (Box 4, Folder 136)
    - The Expectation of Siam (1925), 1925,1927, 1936, n.d. (Box 4, Folder 137)
    - "Patience with China" New York Times, Newark Evening News, 1927 Apr (Box 4, Folder 138)
    - Japan in the World of Today (1928), 1928-1929 (Box 4, Folder 139)
    - "Ourselves and the League" (1935) New York Times, 1935 Nov (Box 4, Folder 140)
    - One Hundred Years (1936), 1936-1937 (Box 4, Folder 141)
    - One Hundred Years (1936), 1939,1944-1948, 1952, 1955, n.d. (Box 4, Folder 142)
    - "The Japan-China Tragedy and America's Relation to It" (1938) (Box 4, Folder 143)
    - "Why Increased Armament?" (1940) (Box 4, Folder 144)
    - "Do Increased Armaments Prevent War?" World Alliance News Letter (1950) (Box 4, Folder 145)
    - "I Believe in the Future" Guideposts, Presbyterian Tribune (1951), 1951-1952 (Box 4, Folder 146)
    - "Missionaries in China" (1951) (Box 4, Folder 147)
    - "A Christmas Benediction" Presbyterian Tribune (1953), 1953-1954 (Box 4, Folder 148)
    - Memoirs of a Centenarian (1957), 1957 Nov (Box 4, Folder 149)
    - Memoirs of a Centenarian (1957), 1957 Dec (Box 4, Folder 150)
    - Memoirs of a Centenarian (1957), 1958 (Box 4, Folder 151)
    - Memoirs of a Centenarian (1957), 1959, 1961, n.d. (Box 4, Folder 152)
    - Miscellaneous, 1900-1917 (Box 4, Folder 153)
    - Miscellaneous, 1921-1940, 1950-1958, n.d. (Box 4, Folder 154)
  - Correspondence Re: Missions
    - Africa, 1906, 1908 (Box 5, Folder 155)
    - China, 1903, 1906-1908 (Box 5, Folder 156)
    - China, 1909 (Box 5, Folder 157)
    - China, 1913-1914, 1916, 1920 -1923, 1946 (Box 5, Folder 158)
    - China, 1901 (Box 5, Folder 159)
    - Colombia, 1914, 1916, 1921 (Box 5, Folder 160)
    - India, 1902 (Box 5, Folder 161)
    - Japan, 1909-1910, 1924, 1926-1928 (Box 5, Folder 162)
    - Korea, 1903-1909, 1915-1929,1945, 1952-1953, n.d. (Box 5, Folder 163)
    - Laos, 1901, 1908 (Box 5, Folder 164)
    - Manchuria, 1909, 1927-1928 (Box 5, Folder 165)
    - Philippine Islands, 1905-(1923) 1927 (Box 5, Folder 166)
    - Siam, 1902-1932 (Box 5, Folder 167)
    - Syria, 1902 (Box 5, Folder 168)
    - Syria, 1907-1908, 1936 (Box 5, Folder 169)
    - Other Countries, "all the Missions", 1902,1907, 1911,1925, 1928 (Box 5, Folder 170)
  - Correspondence Re: Anniversaries
    - 25 years with the Presbyterian Board of Foreign Missions: A-B, 1920 (Box 6, Folder 171)
    - C-F, 1920 (Box 6, Folder 172)
    - G-H, 1920 (Box 6, Folder 173)
    - J-K, 1920 (Box 6, Folder 174)
    - L-M, 1920 (Box 6, Folder 175)
    - N-P, 1920 (Box 6, Folder 176)
    - R, 1920 (Box 6, Folder 177)
    - S-T, 1920 (Box 6, Folder 178)
    - V-Z, 1920 (Box 6, Folder 179)
    - 50th Wedding: A-E, 1933 (Box 6, Folder 180)
    - F-M, 1933 (Box 6, Folder 181)
    - P-W, 1933 (Box 6, Folder 182)
    - 50th wedding, Telegrams, 1933 (Box 6, Folder 183)
    - 60th wedding: B-D, 1943 (Box 6, Folder 184)
    - E-H, 1943 (Box 6, Folder 185)
    - J-M, 1943 (Box 6, Folder 186)
    - N-W, 1943 (Box 6, Folder 187)
    - 50 years with Presbyterian Board of Foreign Missions, 1946 (Box 6, Folder 188)
    - 70th Birthday; C-W, 1926 (Box 7, Folder 189)
    - 75th Birthday; C-W, 1931 (Box 7, Folder 190)
    - 77th Birthday; Wise, Stephen, 1933 (Box 7, Folder 191)
    - 80th Birthday; A-L, 1936 (Box 7, Folder 192)
    - 80th Birthday; M-X, 1936 (Box 7, Folder 193)
    - 86th Birthday; Gamewell, Frank, 1942 (Box 7, Folder 194)
    - 87th Birthday; Speer-Wise, 1943
    - 90th Birthday; A-L, 1946 (Box 7, Folder 195)
    - 90th Birthday; M-W, 1946 (Box 7, Folder 196)
    - 90th Birthday, Telegrams, 1946 (Box 7, Folder 197)
    - 91st Birthday, A-W., 1947 (Box 7, Folder 198)
    - 94th Birthday; Abbott, 1950 (Box 7, Folder 198)
    - 95th Birthday, B-V, 1951 (Box 7, Folder 199)
    - 96th Birthday, F-S, 1952 (Box 7, Folder 200)
    - 97th Birthday; Ahrens, 1953 (Box 7, Folder 201)
    - 98th Birthday, A-S, 1954 (Box 7, Folder 201)
    - 99th Birthday, A-W, 1955 (Box 7, Folder 202)
    - 99th Birthday, Telegrams, 1955 (Box 7, Folder 203)
    - 100th Birthday, A-G, 1956 (Box 7, Folder 204)
    - 100th Birthday, H-P, 1956 (Box 7, Folder 205)
    - 100th Birthday, R-W, 1956 (Box 7, Folder 206)
    - 100th Birthday, Telegrams, 1956 (Box 7, Folder 207)
    - 100th Birthday; Bound volume of letters from the Church Peace Union and the World Alliance for Friendship through Religion, 1956 (Box 7, Folder 208)
    - 101st Birthday, B-W, 1957 (Box 7, Folder 209)
    - 101st Birthday, Telegrams, 1957 (Box 7, Folder 210)
    - 102nd Birthday, A-J, 1958 (Box 7, Folder 211)
    - 102nd Birthday, K-Y, 1958 (Box 7, Folder 212)
    - 103rd Birthday, B-J, 1959 (Box 8, Folder 213)
    - 103rd Birthday, L-W, 1959 (Box 8, Folder 214)
    - 103rd Birthday, Telegrams, 1959 (Box 8, Folder 215)
    - 104th Birthday, A-W, 1960 (Box 8, Folder 216)
    - 104th Birthday, Telegrams, 1960 (Box 8, Folder 217)
    - 105th Birthday, B-W, 1961 (Box 8, Folder 218)
    - 105th Birthday, Telegrams, 1961 (Box 8, Folder 219)
    - 106th Birthday, A-E, 1962 (Box 8, Folder 220)
    - 106th Birthday, F-O, 1962 (Box 8, Folder 221)
    - 106th Birthday, P-W, 1962 (Box 8, Folder 222)
    - 106th Birthday, Telegrams, 1962 (Box 8, Folder 223)
    - Undated birthday greetings (Box 8, Folder 224)
  - Correspondence Re: Retirement
    - A-B, 1929 (Box 9, Folder 225)
    - C-D, 1929 (Box 9, Folder 226)
    - E-F, 1929 (Box 9, Folder 227)
    - G-H, 1929 (Box 9, Folder 228)
    - L, 1929 (Box 9, Folder 229)
    - M, 1929 (Box 9, Folder 230)
    - N-R, 1929 (Box 9, Folder 231)
    - S-W, 1929 (Box 9, Folder 232)
    - Bound volume of letters from members of the Chosen Mission, Korea (Box 9, Folder 233)
  - Correspondence Re: Illness and Sympathy
    - Operation, B-W, 1922 (Box 10, Folder 234)
    - Operation, McDowell, Ruland, Wise, 1941 (Box 10, Folder 235)
    - Death of Arthur J. Brown, A-K, 1963 (Box 10, Folder 236)
    - Death of Arthur J. Brown, L-P, 1963 (Box 10, Folder 237)
    - Death of Arthur J. Brown, R-W no surname, 1963 (Box 10, Folder 238)
    - Death of Arthur J. Brown, Telegrams, 1963 (Box 10, Folder 239)
    - Death of Arthur J. Brown, Jr., B-S, 1959 (Box 10, Folder 240)
    - Death of Elliott W. Brown, A-R, 1941 (Box 10, Folder 241)
    - Death of Jennie E. Brown, A-K, 1945 (Box 10, Folder 242)
    - Death of Jennie E. Brown, M-Z, 1945 (Box 10, Folder 243)
    - Death of Jennie E. Brown, Telegrams, 1945 (Box 10, Folder 244)
- Diaries and Enclosures, 1901-1902, 1909; Series II
  This section is composed of two parts. The seventeen volumes of Arthur J. Brown's 1901-1902 diary are arranged in chronological order. Enclosures from the volumes are located in separate folders immediately following the text. (e.g., "Book XI, Text", "Book XI, Enclosures") The six volumes of Arthur J. Brown's 1909 diary and the enclosures are arranged in the same manner as the above.
  - Book I, Text: New York, U.S.A. - Tokyo, Japan, 1901 Feb 11-1901 Apr 8 (Box 11, Folder 1)
  - Book I, Enclosures: Clipping - pp 64-65 (Box 11, Folder 2)
  - Book II, Text: Tokyo, Japan - Kom Dong, Korea, 1901 Apr 8-1901 May 2 (Box 11, Folder 3)
  - Book II, Enclosures: Note from J.D. Davis - p. 42 (Box 11, Folder 4)
  - Book III, Text: Kum Dong, Korea - Wei Hien, China, 1901 May 1-1901 May 27 (Box 11, Folder 5)
  - Book IV, Text: Wei Hein, China - T'ai Shan, "the sacred mountain of China", 1901 May 28-1901 Jun 12 (Box 11, Folder 6)
  - Book IV, Enclosures: Clipping p. 134, Clipping and Pamphlet p. 174 (Box 11, Folder 7)
  - Book V, Text: T'ai Shan, "the sacred mountain of China" Pao-ting-fu, China, 1901 Jun 13-1901 Jul 5 (Box 11, Folder 8)
  - Book VI, Cover and Text (a pad): Peking, China, 1901 Jul 9-l8 (Box 11, Folder 9)
  - Book VI, Enclosures: Extract of "Eleventh Annual Report of Peking University" re: indemnity - p. 16 (Box 11, Folder 10)
  - Book VII, Text: Chefoo, China - Tsinglan, China, 1901 Jul 19-1901 Aug 11 (Box 11, Folder 11)
  - Book VII, Enclosures: Clipping (Box 11, Folder 12)
  - Book VII, Enclosures: Maps of Shantung Province:1) route suggested to Brown by F.H. Chalfant;2) locations of Protestant missions;3) "Mail Routes of Am. Pres. Miss. Service" (Box 11, Folder 13)
  - Book VIII, Text: Tsinglan, China - Canton, China, 1901 Aug 13-1901 Sep 15 (Box 11, Folder 14)
  - Book VIII, Enclosures: Clipping p. 75, Program - p. 86, Clipping re: McKinley Assassination - p. 119, Note from Henry V. Noyes - p. 143 (Box 11, Folder 15)
  - Book IX, Text: Canton, China - Iloilo, Philippine Islands, 1901 Sep 15-1901 Oct 9 (Box 11, Folder 16)
  - Book IX, Enclosures: Clipping p. 12, Clipping re: Dr. Brown p. 22, Estimate - p. 109, Clip ping re: typhoon - p. 117 (Box 11, Folder 17)
  - Is Book X, Text: Manila, Philippine Islands - Bankok, Siam, 1901 Oct 10-1901 Nov 8 (Box 12, Folder 18)
  - Book X, Enclosures: Clippings re: Reception for Mr. and Mrs. Brown p. 15, Clippings re: typhoon - p. 39 (Box 12, Folder 19)
  - Book XI, Text: Bangkok, Siam -- Proa, Laos, 1901 Nov 8-1901 Nov 29 (Box 12, Folder 20)
  - Book XI, Enclosures: Note re: Book XI - pp. 107-l08, Receipt from cook, in Siamese - p. 158, "Memo of Declaration" - p. 195 (Box 12, Folder 21)
  - Book XII, Text: Pre, Laos - Chieng Mai, Laos, 1901 Nov 30-1901 Dec 18 (Box 12, Folder 22)
  - Book XII, Enclosures: Translation of letter re: Suspected adultery case - p. 9 (Box 12, Folder 23)
  - Book XIII, Text: Chieng Mai, 1901 Dec lS- Laos - Bangkok, Siam, 1902 Jan 15 (Box 12, Folder 24)
  - Book XIII, Enclosures: Letter from Laos Mission to Board p. 23, Siamese postage receipt p. Sl, "Press" material - p. 129 (Box 12, Folder 25)
  - Book XIV, Text: Bangkok, Siam - Lucknow, India, 1902 Jan 15-1902 Feb 14 (Box 12, Folder 26)
  - Book XIV, Enclosures: Clipping p. 68, Material re: Rangoon Baptist College - p. 71, Receipt - p. 111, pamphlet - p. 145, Clipping - p. 145 (Box 12, Folder 27)
  - Book X9, Text: Saharanpur, India - Aden, Arabia, 1902 Feb 15-1902 Mar 7 (Box 12, Folder 28)
  - Book XV, Enclosures: Clippings opp. p. 1, p. 4k, p. 46, p. 62, p. 132 (Box 12, Folder 29)
  - Book XVI, Text: Aden, Arabia - Jaffa, Palestine, 1902 Mar 8-1902 Apr 7 (Box 12, Folder 30)
  - Book XVI, Enclosures: Clippings pp. 4-5, p. 12, p. 133, Cover of a Menu - p. 172 (Box 12, Folder 31)
  - Book XVII, Text: Beirut, Syria - New York, 1902 Apr 7-1902 May 17 (Box 12, Folder 32)
  - Book XXII, Enclosures: Note re: Beirut Conference - pp. 80-8l (Box 12, Folder 33)
  - Book I, Text: New York, U.S.A. - Tokyo, Japan, 1909 Jul 27-1909 Aug 30 (Box 13, Folder 34)
  - Book II, Text: Tokyo, Japan - Seoul, Korea, 1909 Aug 31-1909 Sep 15 (Box 13, Folder 35)
  - Book II, Enclosures: Three calling cards -1909 Sep 9-10 (Box 13, Folder 36)
  - Book III, Text: Seoul, Korea - Port Arthur, Japan, 1909 Sep 15-1909 Oct 6 (Box 13, Folder 37)
  - Book III, Enclosures: List 1909 Sep 30, Korean railroad time table - 1909 Oct 1 (Box 13, Folder 38)
  - Book IV, Text: Port Arthur, Japan - Nanking, China, 1909 Oct 6-1909 Oct 24 (Box 13, Folder 39)
  - Book IV, Enclosures: Calling card 1909 Oct 6-7, Memorial -, 1909 Oct 17 (Box 13, Folder 40)
  - Train schedule - 1909 Oct 20, Editorial 1909 Oct 20-21, Clipping - 1909 Oct 20-21
  - Book V, Text: Nanking, China - Chefoo, China, 1909 Oct 25-1909 Nov 18 (Box 13, Folder 41)
  - Book VI, Text: Chefoo, China - 1909 Nov l8- New York, U.S.A., 1909 Dec 21 (Box 13, Folder 42)
  - Misc. enclosure (Box 13, Folder 43)
- Writings, 1890-1962; Series III